optimalprint.com 2015-04-20

# Privacy Policy

Back

## Part of Optimalprint's Terms and Conditions

Optimalprint knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. By visiting our Site and any of the sites offered by Optimalprint, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. For question on the Privacy Policy please contact [privacypolicy@optimalprint.com](mailto:privacypolicy@optimalprint.com). 

## Children:

Optimalprint does not sell services for purchase by children. If you are under 18, you may use our services only with involvement of a parent or guardian. 

## Information You Give Us

We receive and store any information or content that you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as facilitating when you reorder print material, responding to your requests, providing our services (e.g., storage of picture, images and logos), and in other ways in communicating with you. 

## Automatic Information

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many Websites, we use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses our Sites. Examples of the information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform; the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) click stream to, through, and from our Website, including date and time. We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

## Security of Your Personal Information 

Optimalprint is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always choose to log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. 

While there are always risks associated with providing personal data, whether in person, by phone or via the internet or other technologies, and no system of technology is completely safe or "tamper"/"hacker" proof, Optimalprint has endeavoured to take reasonable precautions which are appropriate to the nature of the information to prevent and minimize such risks in connection with your use of this site. 

## Eligibility and Account Administration 

Optimalprint's policy is to request that "Minors" (the age of Minors is determined by local law where you reside) do not make purchases or engage in other legal acts on the Site without the consent of a parent or legal guardian, unless permitted by applicable local law. You must be 18 years or older to create a user account on Optimalprint. By signing up for a user account you represent and warrant that you are 18 years or older and that you in addition have the right, authority and capacity to understand, agree and comply with these conditions and the Terms of Use. 

When registering you must provide accurate, complete and true registration information. If you have been provided with a default password for registration we advise you to change it immediately for security purposes. Upon initial registration you will be asked to create a username and password, you will be responsible for keeping these confidential, and for all activities relating to your chosen username. 

## Image Gallery

Pictures, images or logos uploaded to your image gallery will be protected from any external access. To access them, you will need to enter your usename and password. 

## Personal Information Shared 

We share information but only as described below. Otherwise we will not provide your personal information without your consent. 

## Business Transfer

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or their assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, if Optimalprint or all or substantially all of its assets were ever to be acquired, customer information will, of course, be one of the transferred assets. 

## Advertisers

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. 

## Agents

We engage other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include processing credit card payments, providing marketing assistance, providing customer services, sending postal mail and email to you, removing repetitive information from customer lists, and analyzing data. These persons have access to personal information needed to perform their functions. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information that you provide to Optimalprint for any secondary purposes. 

## Compliance

We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with law; enforce or apply our agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Optimalprint, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

## Cookies 

A cookie is a small text file, alphanumeric identifiers, that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies contain information that can later be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. 

Optimalprint Web sites use "cookies" to enable you to sign in to our services, help personalize your online experience and control the flow of the ordering processes by maintaining the state of your online transactions. By showing how and when our visitors use Optimalprint's Site, the use of cookies allows Optimalprint to continue to improve the sites. This site also makes use of cookies for website traffic analysis and anonymous demographic profiling. 

If you do not wish to receive cookies, or want to be notified of when they are placed, you may set your web browser to do so, if your browser so permits. Please understand that if cookies are turned off, you may not be able to view certain parts of this site that may enhance your visit. 

Some of our business partners whose content is linked to or from this site may also use cookies. However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. 

Third parties we partner with may place anonymous cookies on your browser and may send their own cookies to your cookie file. 

## Spam

This Site should not be used to send or use e-cards, e-mails, SMS or any other electronic documents in any manner that would constitute the transmission of Spam, SMS or unsolicited e-mails. Automating the creation and/or transmission of e-cards, e-mails or any other electronic documents by the use of scripting or any programs is strictly prohibited. The number of e-cards, SMS, e-mails or any other electronic documents that you can send can at any point, be limited by Optimalprint. Likewise, Optimalprint reserves the right, in its sole discretion, at any time, and without prior notice, to limit the number of recipients to which you may send e-cards, SMSs, e-mails or any other electronic documents. 

You agree that you are responsible for protecting your password and controlling access to your registered account and that you will be responsible for all orders placed or other actions that are taken through your registered account.
